wageworks.com 2019-11-18

# 

                                                                                                                   01/05/18
                                                   NEW PRIVACY POLICY
Effective Date: October 2, 2017
Download and/or print this Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”)
Privacy Policy Scope
Welcome! An overview of this WageWorks Privacy Policy is provided below. To see the full text, click on the links.
Click to view our Terms of Use as well as Additional Terms.
•   Your Choices and Your CA Privacy Rights                 • Use of Information
    You have certain choices regarding information            The information WageWorks collects is used for a
    collection and communications options explained in        variety of purposes as detailed in this Privacy
    Section 11, including:                                    Policy.      For example, your information helps
                                                              WageWorks provide and improve our services,
    -- California residents have certain privacy rights       communicate with you, assist your employer/plan
       detailed in Section 12                                 sponsor in administering your benefits plan, provide
                                                              you the Services you choose, and operate
    -- Although WageWorks does not look for or                WageWorks’ business. More in Section 2
       respond to “do not track” signals, you can find
       information on tracking technologies in Section      • Sharing of Information
       1.B and certain choice options regarding Tracking      -- Subject to applicable law, WageWorks may share
       Technologies in Section 11                                the information WageWorks receives from or
                                                                 about you via the Services (or give others access
    -- Your options regarding accessing and changing             to it), including your Personal Information, for a
       certain of your Personal Information are available        variety of purposes, as detailed in this Privacy
       in Section 10                                             Policy. More in Section 3. These include, without
                                                                 limitation:
    --     Your     options      regarding     promotional
       communications are explained in Section 11; and          ▪ to deliver and improve WageWorks’ services;
                                                                ▪ to assist your employer in administering your
    -- Children’s and minors’ privacy rights, and notice            benefits plan and facilitate your receipt of
       to parents of these rights, are explained in Section         benefits;
       9                                                        ▪ to facilitate your third party requests and
                                                                    communications;
•   Collection of Information                                   ▪ in connection with corporate transactions (e.g.,
    -- WageWorks may ask you to provide Personal                    merger or sale);
       Information (e.g., name, address, e-mail, phone          ▪ to display your posts or send your messages
       number, bank or payment account numbers, etc.),              (More in Section 5); and
       as well as other information (e.g., employer/plan        ▪ in connection with your use of third-party
       sponsor, program participation information, etc.),           services (More in Section 6);
       which may be required to access certain content,
       features, and functionality. More in Section 1.A       -- However, WageWorks obtains your consent (e.g.,
                                                                 opt-in, opt-out), before knowingly sharing
    -- WageWorks and third parties may collect
                                                                 Personal Information with third parties for their
       information from you automatically as you access
                                                                 own direct marketing purposes.
       the Services (e.g., information about the devices
       you use to access the Services and your usage          -- WageWorks may share your non-Personal
                                                                  activities). More in Section 1.B

     -- Subject to applicable law, this may include use of     •    Protected Health Information (“PHI”)
         cookies and other technologies to keep track               When we receive PHI in the course of performing
         of your interactions with the Services, to offer           services for an entity subject to HIPAA (a “covered
         you a more personalized and relevant                       entity”) or state health information privacy laws,
         experience. More in Section 1.B                            we treat and protect the PHI consistent with our
                                                                    obligations under HIPAA, applicable state health
       -- The information WageWorks receives via                    information privacy laws and our contractual
         the Services may be combined with                          obligations to the covered entity (e.g., a group
         informationWageWorks receives from third                   health plan).
         parties and sources outside of the Services.
         More in Section1.C.                                  •    Questions and How to Contact Us
                                                                   For more information about WageWorks’ privacy
     -- WageWorks’ policies and practices regarding                practices regarding the Services, read the full
         Personal Information collected from children              Privacy Policy. You can also contact WageWorks
         are explained in Section 9 Information,                   by         sending          an        email        to
         aggregate and/or de-identified information about          PrivacyPolicy@WageWorks.com if you have
         you except as prohibited by applicable law.               questions or concerns.
                                                              •    Table of Contents
                                                                   For a clickable table of contents that will help you
                                                                   find and navigate to all the sections of the full
                                                                   Privacy Policy.
FULL WAGEWORKS PRIVACY POLICY
Thank you for visiting an online service (e.g., website, software, or app) that posts a link to this Privacy Policy (the
“Online Services”) owned or operated by WageWorks, Inc. (“WageWorks”). This Privacy Policy will provide you with
information as to how WageWorks collects, uses, and shares information about you, including the choices WageWorks
offers with respect to that information, and applies to your use of any Online Services, regardless of how you access or use
it and your submission of information to us offline in connection with our benefit administration services for employer/plan
sponsors (“Administrative Services”). Collectively, Online Services and Administrative Services are collectively
“Services”. For certain Services, there may be additional notices about information practices and choices. Please read those
additional privacy disclosures to understand how they apply to you. In addition, any privacy obligations in our services
agreements with our customers (e.g., with employer/plan sponsors for program services and in some cases with individual
program participants) shall prevail in the event of a conflict with our Services Privacy Policy, including with regard to our
Services. Click to view our Terms of Use and Additional Terms.
By visiting or otherwise using the Services, you agree to the Services’ Terms of Use and consent to WageWorks’ data
collection, use, and disclosure practices, and other activities as described in this Privacy Policy, and any additional privacy
statements that may be posted on an applicable part of the Service. If you do not agree and consent, please discontinue use
of the Services, and uninstall Online Services downloads and applications.
1.        INFORMATION WE COLLECT.
          A.       Information About You That You Provide.
          WageWorks, and/or its Service Providers (defined below), may collect information you provide directly to
WageWorks and/or its Service Providers via the Services. For example, WageWorks collects information when you use or
register for the Online Services, subscribe to, or access, benefit programs via the Online Services, subscribe to notifications,
post on the Online Services, or communicate or transact through the Online Services or submit information in connection
with the Administrative Services. In addition, when you interact with Third-Party Services (defined in Section 6 below),
you may be able to provide information to those third parties. For more information on Third-Party Services’ data
collection and practices go to Section 6. For more information on Service Provider data collection and practices go to
Section 3.                                                                                                                    2

          Information WageWorks, its Service Providers and/or Third-Party Services may collect may include: (1)
personally identifiable information, which is information that identifies you personally, such as your first and last name, e-
mail address, phone number, address, Social Security number, and full payment or banking account number (“Personal
Information”); protected health information as defined by the federal HIPAA law or applicable state healthcare primary
laws (“PHI”); and (3) demographic information, such as your and/or your dependents’ gender, age, zip code, and recent
and upcoming transactions (“Demographic Information”). To the extent permitted by applicable law, Demographic
Information is “non-Personal Information” (i.e., data that is not Personal Information or PHI under this Privacy Policy).
In addition, Personal Information, including, without limitation, WageWorks-Collected PI (defined below), once “de-
identified” (i.e., the removal or modification of the personally identifiable elements, or the extraction of non-personally
identifiable elements) is also non-Personal Information and may be used and shared without obligation to you, except as
prohibited by applicable law (for Client-service PHI (defined in Section 4 below), HIPAA de-identification standards will
be applied). To the extent any non-Personal Information is combined by or on behalf of WageWorks with Personal
Information WageWorks itself collects directly from you on the Services (“WageWorks-Collected PI”), WageWorks will
treat the combined data as WageWorks-Collected PI under this Privacy Policy.
          B.        Information Collected Automatically.
          WageWorks, its Service Providers, and/or Third-Party Services may also automatically collect certain information
about you when you access or use the Services (“Usage Information”). Usage Information may include IP address, device
identifier, browser type, operating system, information about your use of the Services, and data regarding network
connected hardware (e.g., computer or mobile device). Except to the extent required by applicable law (e.g., in some
circumstances under HIPAA and state laws regarding PHI), or to the extent Usage Information is combined by or on behalf
of WageWorks with WageWorks-Collected PI, WageWorks does not consider Usage Information (including, without
limitation, unique device identifiers) to be Personal Information or WageWorks-Collected PI. For more information on
Third-Party Services’ data collection and practices go to Section 6. For more information on Service Provider data
collection and practices go to Section 3. For information on choices some these third parties may offer you regarding
automated data collection go to Section 11.
The methods that may be used on the Services to collect Usage Information include:
     o    Log Information: Log information is data about your use of the Services, such as IP address, browser type,
          Internet service provider, referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamps, and related data, and may be
          stored in log files.
     o    Information Collected by Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies: Cookies, web beacons (also known as
          “tracking pixels”), embedded scripts, in-app tracking methods and other tracking technologies now and hereafter
          developed (“Tracking Technologies”) may be used to collect information about interactions with the Services or
          e-mails, including information about your browsing and purchasing behavior.
                   Cookies
                    A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s device, which may be session ID cookies or tracking
                    cookies. Session cookies make it easier for you to navigate the Services and expire when you close your
                    browser. Tracking cookies remain longer and help in understanding how you use the Services, and
                    enhance your user experience. Cookies may remain on your hard drive for an extended period of time. If
                    you use your browser’s method of blocking or removing cookies, some but not all types of cookies may
                    be deleted and/or blocked and as a result some features and functionalities of the Services may not work.
                    A Flash cookie (or locally shared object) is a data file which may be placed on a device via the Adobe
                    Flash plug-in that may be built-in to or downloaded by you to your device. HTML5 cookies can be
                    programmed through HTML5 local storage. Flash cookies and HTML5 cookies are locally stored on your
                    device other than in the browser and browser settings won’t control them. To identify certain types of
                    local shared objects on your device and adjust your settings, please visit:
                    www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html. The Services
                    may associate some or all of these types of cookies with your devices.
                                                                                                                                3

                   Web Beacons (“Tracking Pixels”)
                   Web beacons are small graphic images, also known as “Internet tags” or “clear gifs,” embedded in web
                   pages and e-mail messages. Web beacons may be used, without limitation, to count the number of visitors
                   to the Services, to monitor how users navigate the Services, and to count content views.
                   Embedded Scripts
                   An embedded script is programming code designed to collect information about your interactions with
                   the Services. It is temporarily downloaded onto your computer from WageWorks’ web server, or from a
                   third party with which WageWorks works, and is active only while you are connected to the Services, and
                   deleted or deactivated thereafter.
                   In-App Tracking Methods
                   There are a variety of Tracking Technologies that may be included in mobile applications, and these are
                   not browser-based like cookies and cannot be controlled by browser settings.
WageWorks is giving you notice of the Tracking Technologies and your choices regarding them explained in Section 11 so
that your consent to encountering them is meaningfully informed.
         C.        Information WageWorks Collects From Other Sources.
         WageWorks may also obtain information about you from other sources, including our employer/plan sponsors and
benefit provider clients (“Clients”), Service Providers and Third-Party Services, and combine that with WageWorks-
Collected PI. Notwithstanding anything to the contrary, except (i) for Personal Information and Client-service PHI, and (ii)
to the extent such data is combined by or on behalf of WageWorks with WageWorks-Collected PI, this Privacy Policy is
not intended to limit WageWorks’ activities regarding such third-party-sourced, or non-Services-sourced information
(including Personal Information), and such data will only be treated as WageWorks-Collected PI to the extend it is
combined with WageWorks-Collected PI. WageWorks is not responsible or liable for the accuracy of the information
provided by third parties or for third party policies or practices.
Return to navigation
2.       HOW WE USE THE INFORMATION WE OBTAIN.
         WageWorks may use information about you, including WageWorks-Collected PI and other Personal Information,
for any purposes not inconsistent with WageWorks’ statements under this Privacy Policy, or otherwise made at the point of
collection, and not prohibited by applicable law, including, without limitation, the following:
     •   Facilitate, manage, personalize, and improve your online experience;
     •   Allow you to participate in the features and service offerings we make available on or via the Services;
     •   Assist your employer/plan sponsor in administering your benefits (e.g., produce debit card, produce and send
         statements and other communications, remit payments to clients, fulfill transit passes, pay or reimburse claims,
         adjudicate transactions, make deposits and determine and report eligibility);
     •   Process your registration, manage your account and/or upload your User Generated Content (“UGC”). (For more
         information on how UGC is treated under the Services’ Terms of Use in Section 2 For more on the public nature
         of UGC, see Section 5);
     •   Transact with you, provide services or information you request, respond to your comments, questions and
         requests,serve you content, and send you notices;
     •   Our marketing (as permitted by applicable law) and other purposes;
                                                                                                                           4

     •    Improve the Services, and our other services, and for any other internal business purposes;
     •    Tailor our content and offers (as permitted by applicable law);
     •    Fulfill other purposes disclosed at the time you provide Personal Information or Client-service PHI, or otherwise
          where we are legally permitted to do so and doing so is not inconsistent with an express privacy commitment we
          have made to you; and
     •    Prevent and address fraud, breach of policies or terms, and threats or harm and to comply with applicable law, and
          law enforcement or other legal processes, and government requests.
Return to navigation
3.        INFORMATION WE SHARE WITH THIRD PARTIES.
          As permitted by applicable law, WageWorks may share non-Personal Information, and Personal Information that
is not deemed WageWorks-Collected PI hereunder, or Client-service PHI, provided that we are not aware of restrictions on
our use or sharing, with third parties or for any purpose. WageWorks’ sharing of WageWorks-Collected PI and Client-
service PHI are, however, subject to the following:
        •    Marketing: Subject to your communications choices explained in Section 11.D, and the rights of California
             residents explained in Section 12, we may use your Personal Information to send you marketing
             communications. WageWorks will not share your WageWorks-Collected PI with third parties, for their own
             direct marketing purposes, except in connection with Corporate Transactions (defined below) absent your
             consent (which may be by means of third party interaction described in the next bullet point). Your HIPAA PHI
             will be used or disclosed for marketing purposes only in accordance with the requirements of HIPAA.
        •    Your Disclosure or Consent: As more fully described in Section 5 (Information You Disclose Publicly or to
             Others) and Section 6 (Third-Party Content, Third-Party Services, Social Features, and Analytics), your
             activities on the Services may, by their nature, result in the sharing of your WageWorks-Collected Personal
             Information (as well as your other Personal Information and your non-Personal Information) with third parties
             and by engaging in these activities you consent to that and further sharing and disclosure to third parties. Such
             third party data receipt and collection is subject to the privacy and business practices of that third party, not
             WageWorks.
          WageWorks may also share any information about you (including, without limitation, WageWorks-Collected PI)
for any purposes not inconsistent with this Privacy Policy, or otherwise not prohibited by applicable law, including, without
limitation:
     •    Clients or Program Sponsors, in connection with their employment-related and/or benefits-related programs and
          activities, concerning you;
     •    WageWorks’ agents, vendors, consultants, and other service providers (collectively “Service Providers”) may
          receive, or be given access to your information, including, without limitation, Personal Information, Demographic
          Information, and Usage Information, in connection with their work on WageWorks’ behalf, provided however, (i)
          your Client-service PHI will remain subject to HIPAA and state health information privacy obligations; and (ii)
          WageWorks does not authorize its Service Providers to use WageWorks-Collected PI provided by WageWorks to
          the Service Providers to send you direct marketing messages other than related to WageWorks absent your
          consent. Service Providers may include custodian banks, payment vendors, job application platforms, statement
          and communications vendors, printed materials fulfillment vendors, eligible providers, health plan carriers, card
          fulfillment vendors, transportation and parking agencies, lockbox providers, call centers, customer service
          vendors, claim process vendors, data protection vendors, and data storage and processing vendors. For more
          information on choices Service Providers may offer you in Section 11.
                                                                                                                             5

     •    To comply with the law, law enforcement or other legal process, and in response to a government request; and
     •    If WageWorks believes your actions are inconsistent with WageWorks’ terms of use, user agreements, applicable
          terms or policies, or to protect the rights, property, life, health, security and safety of WageWorks, the Services or
          its users, or any third party.
          We will only share your Client-service PHI with third parties, to the applicable Client(s), as directed or permitted
by you or as otherwise permitted or required by applicable law.
          WageWorks may share your Client-service PHI and WageWorks-Collected Personal Information (as well as your
other Personal Information and your non-Personal Information), in connection with or during negotiations of any proposed
or actual merger, purchase, sale, joint venture, or any other type of acquisition or business combination of all or any portion
of WageWorks assets, or transfer of all or a portion of WageWorks’ business to another company (“Corporate
Transactions”).
          In addition, in conjunction with laws and regulations enforced by the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission
(“EEOC”), the Office of Federal Contract Compliance Programs (“OFCCP”) and similar state and local regulatory
agencies, we may ask you to provide us with self-identifying information (such as veteran status, gender and ethnicity).
Providing such self-identifying information is voluntary, but if you do provide us with such information, we may submit
that information, to the EEOC, the OFCCP and similar state and local regulatory agencies or otherwise use or disclose it for
business-related purposes, including, without limitation, responding to information requests, fulfilling regulatory reporting
requirements and defending against employment related complaints.
Return to navigation
4.        PROTECTED HEALTH INFORMATION (“PHI”).
          Notwithstanding anything in this Privacy Policy to the contrary, when we receive PHI in the course of performing
services for a HIPAA covered entity or an entity subject to state health information privacy laws (“Client-service PHI”),
we treat and protect the Client-service PHI consistent with our obligations under HIPAA, applicable state health
information privacy laws and our contractual obligations to the covered entity (e.g., a group health plan).
Return to navigation
5.        INFORMATION YOU DISCLOSE PUBLICLY OR TO OTHERS.
          The Services may permit you to post or submit UGC including, without limitation, comments and other content,
including Personal Information and Client-service PHI. If you choose to submit UGC to any public area of the Online
Services (e.g., comments to blog posts), your UGC will be considered “public” and will be accessible by anyone, including
WageWorks. Notwithstanding anything to the contrary, unless otherwise explicitly agreed by us, Personal Information and
Client-service PHI included in UGC is not subject to WageWorks’ usage or sharing limitations, or other obligations,
regarding WageWorks-Collected PI, Client-service PHI, or other Personal Information under this Privacy Policy or
otherwise, and may be used and shared by WageWorks and third parties to the fullest extent not prohibited by applicable
law. WageWorks encourages you to exercise caution when making decisions about what you disclose in such public areas.
For more information on how UGC is treated under the Services’ Terms of Use click in Section 2. California minors
should see Section 9 regarding potential removal of certain UGC they have posted on the Online Services.
          Additionally, the Services may offer you the option to send a communication to a friend, your employer or other
contact. If so, WageWorks relies on you to only send to people that have given you permission to do so. The recipient’s
Personal Information you provide (e.g., name, e-mail address) will be used to facilitate the communication, but not used by
WageWorks for any other marketing purpose unless WageWorks obtains consent from that person. Your contact
information and message may be included in the communication.
Return to navigation
                                                                                                                               6

6.        THIRD-PARTY CONTENT, THIRD-PARTY SERVICES, SOCIAL FEATURES, AND ANALYTICS.
          The Services may include hyperlinks to, or include on or in connection with, the Services (e.g., apps, software, and
plug-ins), websites, locations, platforms, applications or services operated by third parties (“Third-Party Service(s)”).
These Third-Party Services may use their own cookies, web beacons, and other Tracking Technology to independently
collect information about you and may solicit Personal Information from you.
          For example, certain functionalities on the Services permit interactions that you initiate between the Services and
certain Third-Party Services, such as third party social networks (“Social Features”). If you use Social Features, and
potentially other Third-Party Services, information you post or provide access to may be publicly displayed on the Services
(see Section 5) or by the Third-Party Service that you use. Similarly, if you post information on a third-party service that
references the Services (e.g., by using a hashtag associated with WageWorks in a tweet or status update), your post may be
used on or in connection with the Services or otherwise by WageWorks. Also, both WageWorks and the third party may
have access to certain information about you and your use of the Services and any Third-Party Service.
          WageWorks may use Google Analytics, Adobe Analytics or other Service Providers for analytics services. These
analytics services may use cookies and other Tracking Technologies to help WageWorks analyze Service users and how
they use the Services. Information generated by these services (e.g., your IP address and other Usage Information) may be
transmitted to and stored by these Service Providers on servers in the U.S. (or elsewhere) and these Service Providers may
use this information for purposes such as evaluating your use of the Services, compiling statistic reports on the Services’
activity, and providing other services relating to Services activity and other Internet usage.
          Except to the extent we combine information we receive from Service Providers, Third-Party Services, or other
third parties with WageWorks-Collected PI, in which case WageWorks will treat the combined information as
WageWorks-Collected PI under this Privacy Policy (see Section 1(c)), data obtained by WageWorks from a third party,
even in association with the Services, is not subject to WageWorks’ limitations regarding WageWorks-Collected PI under
this Privacy Policy, however such data remains subject to any restrictions imposed on WageWorks by the third party, if
any. Otherwise, the information collected, stored, and shared by third parties remains subject to their privacy policies and
practices, including whether they continue to share information with WageWorks, the types of information shared, and your
choices on what is visible to others on Third-Party Services.
          Except as required under applicable law and/or our contractual commitments to covered entities with regard to
Client-service PHI, WageWorks is not responsible for and makes no representations regarding the policies or business
practices of any third parties, including, without limitation, analytics Service Providers and Third-Party Services associated
with the Services, and encourages you to familiarize yourself with and consult their privacy policies and terms of use. See
Section 11 for more on certain choices offered by some third parties regarding their data collection and use, including
regarding analytics.
Return to navigation
7.        DATA SECURITY AND MONITORING.
          WageWorks takes reasonable measures to protect WageWorks-Collected PI (excluding public UGC), and Client-
service PHI, from loss, theft, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. Nevertheless,
transmission via the internet and online digital storage are not completely secure and WageWorks cannot guarantee the
security of your information collected through the Services.
          To help protect you and others, and as permitted by applicable law, WageWorks and its Service Providers may
(but make no commitment to) monitor use of the Services, and may collect and use related information including
WageWorks-Collected PI and other Personal Information for all purposes not prohibited by applicable law or inconsistent
with this Privacy Policy, including, without limitation, to identify fraudulent activities and transactions; prevent abuse of
and investigate and/or seek prosecution for any potential threats to or misuse of the Services; ensure compliance with the
Terms of Use and this Privacy Policy; investigate violations of or enforce these agreements; and otherwise to protect the
rights and property of WageWorks, third parties, and other users. Monitoring may result in the collection, recording, and
analysis of online activity or communications through our Services. If you do not consent to these conditions, you must
discontinue your use of the Services.
                                                                                                                             7

Return to navigation
8.       INTERNATIONAL TRANSFER.
         WageWorks is based in the U.S. and the information WageWorks and its Service Providers collect is governed by
U.S. law. If you are accessing the Services from outside of the U.S., please be aware that information collected through the
Services may be transferred to, processed, stored, and used in the U.S. Data protection laws in the U.S. may be different
from those of your country of residence. Your use of the Services or provision of any information therefore constitutes your
consent to the transfer to and from, processing, usage, sharing, and storage of your information, including Personal
Information, in the U.S. as set forth in this Privacy Policy.
Return to navigation
9.       CHILDREN’S PRIVACY.
         The Services is intended for a general audience and not directed to children less than thirteen (13) years of age.
WageWorks does not intend to collect personal information as defined by the U.S. Children’s Privacy Protection Act
(“COPPA”) (“Children’s Personal Information”) in a manner that is not permitted by COPPA. If we obtain knowledge
that we have collected Children’s Personal Information in a manner not permitted by COPPA, we will remove such data to
the extent required by COPPA.
         Any California residents under the age of eighteen (18) who have registered to use the Services, and who posted
content or information on the Online Services, can request removal by contacting WageWorks by sending an email to
PrivacyPolicy@WageWorks.com, detailing where the content or information is posted and attesting that you posted it.
WageWorks will then make reasonable good faith efforts to remove the post from prospective public view or anonymize it
so the minor cannot be individually identified to the extent required by applicable law. This removal process cannot
ensure complete or comprehensive removal. For instance, third-parties may have republished or archived content by search
engines and others that WageWorks does not control.
Return to navigation
10.      ACCESSING AND CHANGING INFORMATION.
         WageWorks may provide web pages or other mechanisms allowing you to delete, correct, or update some of the
WageWorks-Collected PI, and potentially certain other information about you (e.g., profile and account information).
WageWorks will make good faith efforts to make requested changes in WageWorks’ then-active databases as soon as
practicable, but it is not always possible to completely change, remove or delete all of your information or public postings
from WageWorks’ databases (California minors see Section 9) and residual and/or cached data may remain archived
thereafter. Further, we reserve the right to retain data (a) as required by applicable law; and (b) for so long as reasonably
necessary to fulfill the purposes for which the data is retained except to the extent prohibited by applicable law.
Return to navigation
11.      CHOICES: TRACKING AND COMMUNICATIONS OPTIONS.
         A.        Tracking Technologies Generally. Regular cookies may generally be disabled or removed by tools
available as part of most commercial browsers, and in some instances blocked in the future by selecting certain settings.
Browsers offer different functionalities and options so you may need to set them separately. Also, tools from commercial
browsers may not be effective with regard to Flash cookies (also known as locally shared objects), HTML5 cookies, or
other Tracking Technologies. For information on disabling Flash cookies, go to Adobe’s website. Please be aware that if
you disable or remove these technologies, some parts of the Services may not work and that when you revisit the Services
your ability to limit browser-based Tracking Technologies is subject to your browser settings and limitations.
                                                                                                                           8

          Some app-related Tracking Technologies in connection with non-browser usage (e.g., most functionality of a
mobile app) can only be disabled by uninstalling the app. To uninstall an app, follow the instructions from your operating
system or handset manufacturer.
          Your browser settings may allow you to automatically transmit a “Do Not Track” signal to Services you visit.
Note, however, there is no consensus among industry participants as to what “Do Not Track” means in this context. Like
many Services, WageWorks currently does not alter WageWorks’ practices when WageWorks receives a “Do Not Track”
signal from a visitor’s browser. To find out more about “Do Not Track,” you can visit http://www.allaboutdnt.com, but
WageWorks is not responsible for the completeness or accuracy of this third party information. Some third parties,
however, may offer you choices regarding their Tracking Technologies. One way to potentially identify cookies on our Site
is to add the free Ghostery plug-in to your browser (www.ghostery.com), which according to Ghostery will display for you
traditional, browser-based cookies associated with the web sites (but not mobile apps) you visit and privacy and opt-out
policies and options of the parties operating those cookies. WageWorks is not responsible for the completeness or accuracy
of this tool or third party choice notices or mechanisms. For specific information on some of the choice options offered by
third party analytics and advertising providers, see the next section.
          B.        Analytics and Tracking Technologies. You may exercise choices regarding the use of cookies from
Google Analytics by going to https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout or downloading the Google Analytics Opt-out
Browser Add-on. You may exercise choices regarding the use of cookies from Adobe Analytics by going to
http://www.adobe.com/privacy/opt-out.html under the section labeled “Tell our customers not to measure your use of their
websites or tailor their online ads for you.”
          We may use Oracle Marketing Cloud Services such as Eloqua to provide us with user Services activity
information. Oracle offers users with certain privacy choices, including an opt-out. For more information, see
https://www.oracle.com/marketingcloud/opt-status.html and https://www.oracle.com/legal/privacy/privacy-choices.html.
          You may choose whether to receive some Interest-based Advertising by submitting opt-outs. Some of the
advertisers and Service Providers that perform advertising-related services for us and third parties may participate in the
Digital Advertising Alliance’s (“DAA”) Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising. To learn more about
how you can exercise certain choices regarding Interest-based Advertising, visit http://www.aboutads.info/choices/, and
http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices for information on the DAA’s opt-out program for mobile apps. Some of these
companies may also be members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”). To learn more about the NAI and your
opt-out options for their members, see http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/. Please be aware that, even if you are
able to opt out of certain kinds of Interest-based Advertising, you may continue to receive other types of ads. Opting out
only means that those selected members should no longer deliver certain Interest-based Advertising to you, but does not
mean you will no longer receive any targeted content and/or ads (e.g., from other ad networks). Also, if your browsers are
configured to reject cookies when you visit these opt-out webpages, or you subsequently erase your cookies, use of a
different device or web browsers or use a non-browser-based method of access (e.g., mobile app), your NAI / DAA
browser-based opt-out may not, or may no longer, be effective. WageWorks supports the ad industry’s 2009 Self-
regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising (PDF) and expects that ad networks WageWorks directly engages
to serve you Interest-based Advertising will do so as well, though WageWorks cannot guaranty their compliance.
WageWorks is not responsible for effectiveness of, or compliance with, any third-parties’ opt-out options or programs or
the accuracy of their statements regarding their programs.
C.        Mobile Apps. With respect to WageWorks’ mobile apps (“apps”), you can stop all collection of data generated
by use of the app by uninstalling the app. Also, you may be able to exercise specific privacy choices, such as enabling or
disabling certain features (e.g., push notifications, accessing phone, SMS, device id, data, photos/media/files, etc.), by
adjusting the permissions in your mobile device and/or the app’s settings. Beware that if GPS precise location services are
disabled, other means of establishing or estimating location (e.g., connecting to or proximity to wi-fi, Bluetooth, beacons, or
our networks) may persist.
                                                                                                                              9

          D.       Communications. You can opt out of receiving certain promotional communications (emails or text
messaging) from WageWorks at any time by (i) for promotional e-mails, following the instructions provided in emails to
click on the unsubscribe link, or if available by changing your communication preferences by logging onto your account;
and (ii) for text messages, text back the word, “STOP” and (iii) for app push notifications, turn off push notifications on the
settings of your device and/or the app, as applicable. Please note that your opt-out is limited to the e-mail address or phone
number used and will not affect subsequent subscriptions. If you opt-out of only certain communications, other
subscription communications may continue. Even if you opt-out of receiving promotional communications, WageWorks
may, subject to applicable law, continue to send you non-promotional communications, such as those about your account,
transactions, servicing, or WageWorks’ ongoing business relations.
Return to navigation
12.       YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS.
          We do not share personal information as defined by California Civil Code Section 1798.83 (“Shine The Light
law”) with third parties for their direct marketing purposes absent your consent. If you are a California resident, you may
request information about our compliance with the Shine the Light law by contacting us by email to
PrivacyPolicy@wageworks.com or by sending a letter to WageWorks, Inc., 1100 Park Place #400, San Mateo, CA 94403
(Attention: Legal Counsel/Privacy). Any such request must include "California Privacy Rights Request" in the first line of
the description and include your name, street address, city, state, and ZIP code. Please note that we are only required to
respond to one request per customer each year, and we are not required to respond to requests made by means other than
through this email address or mail address.
          California minors should see “Children’s Privacy” at Section 9 regarding removal of certain content they have
posted.
Return to navigation
13.       YOUR CONNECTICUT PRIVACY RIGHTS.
      Connecticut law requires any person or entity that collects Social Security numbers from Connecticut residents in the
course of business to create a privacy protection policy and to publish or display it publicly. It is our policy to protect the
confidentiality of Social Security numbers in our possession from misuse and improper disclosure by maintaining and
enforcing policies and physical and electronic safeguards against misuse and improper disclosure. Unlawful disclosure of
Social Security numbers is prohibited, and access to them is limited to personnel who need access to such information in
order to perform their job functions.
14.       CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY.
          We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy prospectively effective upon the posting of the revised Privacy
Policy and your use of our Services indicates your consent to the privacy policy posted at the time of use. However, we
will not use your previously collected WageWorks-Collected PI, or Client-service PHI, to the extent it is not collected
under the new privacy policy, in a manner materially different than represented at the time it was collected without your
consent. To the extent any provision of this Privacy Policy is found by a competent tribunal to be invalid or unenforceable,
such provision shall be severed to the extent necessary for the remainder to be valid and enforceable.
Return to navigation
15.       CONTACT US.
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us by email at PrivacyPolicy@wageworks.com or at
WageWorks, Inc., 1100 Park Place #400, San Mateo, CA 94403. (Attention: Legal Counsel/Privacy).
                                                                                                                             10

Return to navigation
//End Privacy Policy//
© WageWorks, Inc. 2017. All Rights Reserved.
                                             11

                                             PRIVACY POLICY SCOPE
Welcome! An overview of the WageWorks Privacy Policy is below. To see the full text, click on the links
provided. This Privacy Policy applies to your use of the Services (e.g., website, software, app, or benefit
administration) that posts a link to this Privacy Policy, regardless of how you access or use it. Click here to
view our Terms of Use.
This Privacy Policy is posted in interactive format to ease your review, especially using smart phones and other
devices with small screens. It is important that you read and understand the entire Privacy Policy before using
the Service.
1.      Information We Collect
        (a)     Information About You That You Provide
        (b)     Information Collected Automatically
        (c)     Information WageWorks Collects From Other Sources
2.      How We Use The Information We Obtain
3.      Information We Share With Third Parties
4.      Protected Health Information (“PHI”)
5.      Information You Disclose Publicly Or To Others
6.      Third-Party Content, Third-Party Services, Social Features, and Analytics
7.      Data Security and Monitoring
8.      International Transfer
9.      Children’s Privacy
10.     Accessing and Changing Information
11.     Choices: Tracking and Communications Options
        (a)     Tracking Technologies Generally
        (b)     Analytics and Tracking Technologies
        (c)     Mobile Apps
        (d)     Communications
12.     Your California Privacy Rights
13.     Your Connecticut Privacy Rights
                                                                                                              12

14. Changes to this Privacy Policy
15. Contact Us
                                   13
